片名: 蝙蝠侠
(哥谭市)
Thank you. Hi. I'd like to go to the Adelphi Hotel.
谢谢你 嗨 我要去亚道夫大饭店
- Excuse me. - I'm sorry. This is my cab.
- 抱歉 - 对不起 车子是我叫的
I was here first!
我先来的呀!
Oh, God.
天呀
Taxi!
计程车!
Let's go across. Come on.
走路过街吧
We'll get one down the road. Hurry.
到那边去叫 走
For God's sake, Harold, can we please just get a taxi?
拜托 哈洛 快叫车呀?
I'm trying to get a...Taxi!
我正在叫计程车!
We're going the wrong way!
方向错了!
Put that away. We'll look like tourists.
吉米 收起来 像土观光客似的
Hi, honey.
嗨 甜心
We'll never get a cab. Let's cut over to Seventh.
在这我们永远叫不到车 我们到第7街再说
- Seventh is that way. - I know where we are!
- 第7街在那边 - 我知道方向!
Hey, mister. Give me a dollar.
先生 赏一块钱吧
- Come on. - How about it? One dollar.
- 快走 - 怎么样? 一块钱而已
Are you deaf? You don't speak English?
你聋了吗? 不会说英语?
Come on! Up here.
快呀! 到这里
Hey, lady...
女士
do the kid a favor. Don't scream.
看小孩的份上 不要叫
Hey, all right.
收获不少
American Express card.
美国运通信用卡
"Don't leave home without it."
"出门别忘此卡"
Get out of here.
滚远点
Let's beat it, man. I don't like it up here.
说实话 伙计 我不喜欢这里
What, are you scared of heights?
怎么 你有恐高症?
I don't know. After what happened to Johnny Gobs...
不知道 强尼的下场使我害怕
Look, man, Johnny Gobs got ripped and took a walk off a roof. No big loss.
强尼是喝醉酒从屋顶掉下去摔死的 没什么好伤心的
No, man, that ain't what I heard at all.
错了 伙计 我听说的不是这样
I heard that the Bat got him.
听说被蝙蝠侠抓走的
The Bat? Give me a break, will you?
蝙蝠侠? 得了吧?
Five stories. Straight down. There wasn't no blood in the body.
从4楼摔下去 身体里一点血也没有
No shit. It was all over the pavement.
胡扯 人行道上一片红
- I'm getting out of here, man. - Shut up, man. Listen to me.
- 我要走了 - 闭嘴 听我说
There ain't no Bat.
根本没有蝙蝠侠
You shouldn't have turned the gun on that kid.
你不该用枪打那个孩子的
You want your cut of this money or not? Now shut up! Shut up.
你究竟要不要你的钱? 大嘴给我闭上! 闭嘴
Don't kill me!
别杀我!
Don't kill me! man.
别杀我! 兄弟
Don't kill me!
别杀我!
I'm not going to kill you. I want you to do me a favor.
我不杀你 有事请你帮忙
I want you to tell all your friends about me.
带个话给你所有朋友
What are you?
你是什么东西?
I'm Batman.
我是蝙蝠侠
Across this nation...
对全美国人而言
the words "Gotham City" are synonymous with crime.
哥谭市就是犯罪的代名词
Our streets are overrun, our public officials are helpless.
街头暴力充斥 政府官员束手无策
As mayor, I promise to root out the source of this corruption...
身为市长 我保证扫清犯罪的根源
Boss Carl Grissom.
包斯卡尔格里森
Now, our new District Attorney, Harvey Dent...
并由新任地方检查官
will carry out that promise.
哈维丹特执行
Harvey
哈维
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you, Mayor Borg. Thank you.
谢谢 布格市长 谢谢
People of Gotham City...
哥谭市民们
I'm a man of few words.
我一向言简意赅
But those words will count, and so will my actions.
不过却一言九鼎 言出必行
Police Commissioner Gordon has informed me...
高登局长说
that he has targeted those businesses...
他已经找出那些
suspected of fronting for the syndicate in this city.
为黑社会的非法营业
Before the week is out...
这星期之内
we are going to knock down their doors...
我们将全面大扫荡
and shed the light of the law on that nest of vipers.
直捣魔窟
Together, we can make this city safe for decent people.
只要大家团结 便可以建设成一个理性高尚的城市
Decent people shouldn't live here.
高尚的人不该住本市
They'd be happier someplace else.
换个地方会更快乐
Pretty tough talk about Carl.
听说卡尔是个铁腕硬汉
Don't worry about it.
你放心好了
If this clown could touch Grissom, I'd have handed him his lungs by now.
那个小丑敢碰格里森一下 早就被我吊死了
If Grissom knew about us...
格里森要知道你我的事
he might hand you something.
你也不会好过的
Don't flatter yourself, angel.
你别往脸上帖金了
He's a tired old man. He can't run this city without me.
他已年迈花甲 缺了我 他控制不了本市
And besides...
再说嘛
he doesn't know.
他也不知道
You don't worry about anything, do you, Jack?
你真的毫不在乎? 杰克
You look fine.
帅哥
I didn't ask.
我没问你
Yeah. Hanging on.
对 好好保重
No. Let me guess.
你别说 让我猜
Giant, menacing, supernatural form. Kind of like a bat.
一只巨大 超级动物 像只蝙蝠
That's it. What are they seeing up there?
没错 上面怎么回事?
They're drinking Drano.
喝了通乐
It's a little weird, Lieutenant.
有点怪异 警官
Thanks for the tip.
谢谢你的情报
Christ. Knox.
要命 又是诺克
Hello, Lt. Eckhardt, I hear we just had us another Bat attack.
你好 艾哈特警官 听说蝙蝠攻击人类
That's what, eight sightings now in just under a month?
一个月之内连续八起?
I hear the Commissioner's even opened a file. True?
听说局长下令彻查 是真的吗?
Sorry, Knox. These two slipped on a banana peel.
抱歉 诺克 这两个人踩香蕉皮跌死的
I'm telling you, man, a giant bat!
我没骗你 是只巨大的蝙蝠!
Keep move.
继续走
Don't be writing this stuff in the newspaper, Knox.
最后别登在报上 诺克
It'll ruin your already useless reputation.
以免毁了报社的声名
Lieutenant, every punk in this town is scared stiff.
警官 全镇的游民都吓得魂不守舍的
Do you know what they say? They say he can't be killed.
知道他们怎么说吗? 说他刀枪不入
They say he drinks blood.
专喝人血
- They say... - I say you're full of shit, Knox.
- 还说 - 我说你满嘴狗臭屁 诺克
You can quote me on that.
这句话可以引述
Is there a 6-foot bat in Gotham City?
哥谭市真的有只6尺蝙蝠吗?
And if so, is he on the police payroll?
他是领警察薪水的吗?
And if so, what's he pulling down, after taxes?
扣了税以后 年薪多少?
Brought you a little snack, Eckhardt.
带给你的小点心 艾哈特
- Why don't you broadcast it? - Shut up and listen.
- 干嘛不去广播? - 闭嘴听我说
Harvey Dent has been sniffing around one of our front companies.
哈维丹特盯上了咱们一家前卫公司
That's my territory. If there's a problem, I deal with it.
我的地盘 任何问题我会处理
Your problems are our problems.
你的问题也是我们的
I answer to Grissom, not to psychos.
我只对格里森负责 不对神经病
Why, Eckhardt, you ought to think about the future.
为什么 艾哈特 你该为未来想想
You mean when you run the show? You ain't got no future, Jack.
你以为你能接管? 你最好别做梦 杰克
You're an A-1 nut-boy, and Grissom knows it.
你是神经加三级 格里森心里有数
Better be sure.
考虑清楚哟
See?
瞧吧?
You can make a good decision when you try.
愿意的话是可以做出明智的决定
Where you been spending your nights?
你在哪过夜的?
I don't care how deeply in debt this festival is, I want a parade.
我不管预算如何 我要举办游行
I want hot dogs, balloons, the whole schemer.
有热狗 汽球 整个策划
We're gonna celebrate this 200th anniversary proudly and publicly.
热热闹闹地庆祝2百周年纪念日
We may be celebrating in bankruptcy court.
还是庆祝破产吧
This festival's $250,000 in the red and we haven't seen one balloon.
债务已经25万 还没看见半个汽球
You fill this square with people, and the businesses will come back here.
只要把人找来 生意自然会有
I think a lot of people might stay away, Mayor. They're scared.
很多人会怕的躲起来 市长
They won't be scared when you get Grissom in that courthouse.
有了格里森干地方检察官 就不用怕了
I promised that, remember?
我承诺过 记得吗?
Welcome, Count Dracula.
欢迎吸血爵士光临
- Had any sightings of Bigfoot lately? - Hey, Knox...
- 最近有没大脚的消息? - 嘿 诺克
- they buried your story on the Batman. - That's what they do to garbage.
- 你的连载已被蝙蝠侠取代了 - 垃圾就该如此处理
This is Pulitzer Prize stuff, guys.
可以得普立兹新闻奖的
Hey, Knox. I got something for you.
诺克 有东西给你
Very funny. You should have a little bit more gore under the fangs, though.
真好笑 獠牙下该画几滴口水的
What a dick.
傻屌一个
Hello, legs.
哈罗 长腿姊姊
I'm reading your stuff.
我在看你的报导
Well, I'm reading yours.
我在看你的美腿
Hi, I'm Vicki Vale.
嗨 我是维琪瓦尔
Yeah, photographer. Vogue, Cosmo. Yeah.
维琪瓦尔 流行和大都会 摄影师
Listen, if you want me to pose nude, you're gonna need a long lens.
对 想拍我裸照的话 得把镜头拉长
Actually, I was in the Corto Maltese.
其实我正在拍战争的东西
A girl could get hurt doing this stuff.
拍那玩意会有危险的
So, what brings you here?
什么风把你吹来的?
I'm here to see some of the wildlife in Gotham City.
来看哥谭市野生动物的
Wildlife? Like what?
野生? 比方说?
Like...bats.
比方说蝙蝠
- Who sent you? - Nobody, really.
- 谁派你来的? - 没人 真的
I just loved your story, and...
我喜欢你的报导
I like bats.
我喜欢蝙蝠
really?
真的?
My pictures, your words. Pulitzer Prize material. Just think.
我的照片加上你的报导 保证得奖 考虑看看
Okay, you're a visionary. You're also the only one who believes me.
算你有远见 也是唯一相信我的人
I need something tangible.
我需要确凿的证据
Gordon's got a file on this. I can't even get him on the phone.
高登有档案 他连我电话都不接
Bruce Wayne's benefit. He'll be there, right?
他会参加布鲁斯韦恩慈善义演 他会去吧?
Yeah. I don't seem to be on the guest list. No.
对 只是名单上没有我 没有
Yes. Yes.
对 对
Yes. Vale, will you marry me?
维琪 你愿意嫁我吗?
- No. - Will you buy me lunch?
- 不要 - 请我吃饭?
- Maybe. - I eat light.
- 有可能 - 我食量不大
Say this...
万一
son of a bitch...
这个王八蛋
makes a connection with us and with Axis Chemicals.
查出艾克斯化学厂和我们有关
What kind of damage are we looking at?
真不知后果会如可?
If he ties us in with Axis Chemicals, we're dead and buried.
万一被他查到了 咱们真的完蛋了
We should move immediately.
我们该立刻采取行动
I say we break into the place...
我建议突击该厂
trash the office...
把办公室捣烂
and make off with the records and say it was industrial espionage.
把纪录毁掉 宣称是工业间谍干的
Smart thinking. That's the way to go. In fact...
聪明 这么做才对 事实上
I'd like you to handle this operation personally.
我要你亲自指挥这个行动
Me?
我?
Hello, sweetheart.
哈罗 甜心
I wonder if you'd mind waiting in the next room?
你不介意去隔壁等吗?
That's all, gentlemen. Thank you.That's all.
没事 各位 谢谢光临 没事了
Carl...
卡尔
can we get somebody else to do this?
可否派别人去?
The fumes in that place...
我受不了化学味
Jack.
杰克
It's an important job.
这次行动关系重大
I need someone I can trust.
我需要个信得过的人
You are my number one guy.
你是我的左右手
Now...
你
don't forget...
别忘了
your lucky deck.
你的幸运牌
My friend...
朋友
your luck is about to change.
你就要走运了
Police Department.
警察局
Get me Lt. Eckhardt.
请接艾哈特警官
Can I help you, sir?
需要我效劳吗? 先生
Thanks. Thank you very much. That's very nice of you.
谢谢 多谢你 你真好
Here you go.
赏你的
- Good evening, ma'am. - A little crowded.
- 晚上好 小姐 - 人多了点
Excuse me.Excuse me...
对不起 对不起
Could you tell me which of these guys is Bruce Wayne?
请教布鲁斯韦恩是谁?
I'm not sure.
我没把握
Thanks anyway.
还是得谢你
Yeah
是呀
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, certainly.
哦 当然
Bet!
快下注!
Eight. I can make that eight.
8点 我一丢就是8点
- I can make that eight. - Place your bets, please.
- 我一丢就是8点 - 请下注
Commissioner! Mrs. Gordon, you look lovely.
局长! 高登太太 你真漂亮
How about that rumor that Commissioner's got a file on the Batman?
局长真的有蝙蝠侠的档案?
That's not true, is it?
不是真的吧?
Knox, for the ninth time, there is no Bat.
诺克 没有什么蝙蝠
If there were, we would find and arrest him.
有的话早抓走了
Would you confirm him? Be straight with me, Commissioner.
你确认吗? 跟我坦白说 局长
- How you making out? - Not good at all.
- 手气还好吧? - 糟透了
Mr. Dent, I love that tie.
丹特先生 我喜欢你的领带
We were discussing the pros and cons of winged vigilantes. What's your stand?
我们正在谈飞行义警的事 你的立场如何?
Mr. Knox, we have enough problems in this city...
诺克先生 本市的问题已经够多了
without worrying about ghosts and goblins.
没暇为鬼力乱神之事操心了
Pardon me, but that's not a denial.
没错 我无法否认
Excuse me, dear. I'll be back.
失陪一下 我马上回来
Isn't anybody going to go on record?
有谁要公开发表一下的?
- Your Honor, great suit. - No comment.
- 阁下 好棒的西装 - 无以置评
- Robert, what's up? - Anonymous tip.
- 什么事? 罗勃 - 匿名情报
Napier's cleaning out Axis Chemicals.
纳皮尔扫荡了艾克斯厂
Why wasn't I told about this? Who's in charge?
为什么没人告诉我? 是谁负责的?
- Eckhardt, sir. - Oh, my God!
- 艾哈特 - 真要命!
Come on, let's go.
咱们走
Commissioner Gordon?
高登先生?
Wait, wait. Living room, dining room, arsenal.
等一下 起居间 餐厅 还是弹药库
Look at this stuff.
瞧瞧这些玩意
Who is this guy?
这家伙是谁?
He gives to all these humanitarian causes, and then collects all this stuff.
一个人道主义者 居然收集这种玩意
He probably does it to get chicks. They like him for his big charity balls.
还不是为了交女人 她们喜欢他的慈善舞会
Don't leave out his very large bankroll.
别忘了他的存款数字
Now, remember, the more they've got, the less they're worth.
越有钱 人越不值钱
Then this guy must be the most worthless guy in America.
那么他八成是全美国 价格最底的人
Check this out. He must have been King of the Wicker People.
你瞧这个 他八成是稻草人之王
Where'd this come from?
这是哪来的?
I have no idea.
我不知道
It's Japanese.
是日本的
How do you know?
你怎么知道?
Because I bought it in Japan.
我打日本买的
- Who are you? - Sorry. Bruce Wayne.
- 你是谁? - 抱歉 布鲁斯韦恩
Alexander Knox.
亚历山大诺克
I read your work. I like it a lot.
我看过你的报导 佩服之至
Thanks. Can I have a grant?
谢了 捐一点吧?
- Vicki Vale. - Hi.
- 维琪瓦尔 - 嗨
- Bruce Wayne. - Are you sure?
- 布鲁斯韦恩 - 没搞错吧?
Yeah, this time.
对 错不了
I've seen your photographs from Corto Maltese, haven't I?
我看过你战争的作品 对吧?
Right.
对
You've got a wonderful eye.
你的眼光独到
Some people think she has two.
该说是两只的
This is an amazing house. I'd like to shoot it sometime if you...
这栋房子好壮观 希望能有机会拍
We need to open a few more cases of the champagne. Will that be all right?
韦恩先生 我们还需要几箱香槟 可以吧?
Sure. Go ahead.
当然 请便
Open, what, six? Six?
开几箱? 6箱?
- Six is good. - Okay.
- 6箱好 - 可以
That's great, six, thanks.
好的 6箱 谢谢
Anyway, you gonna be staying in Gotham for a while?
你会在哥谭市待一阵吗?
I'd love to. I'm intrigued by Alex's giant bat stories.
我很愿意 我对亚历山大的蝙蝠报导很有兴趣
Oh, right. The Batman.
对 蝙蝠侠
That's a little bit light after the war in Corto Maltese, isn't it?
可以调剂一下战争的火药味 对吧?
- What do you do for a living? - Well, I'm involved...
- 你是干哪一行的? - 哦 我
Sir, Commissioner Gordon was compelled to leave.
高登局长想告辞了
Okay, thank you.
好的 谢谢你
Very unexpectedly, sir.
相当出乎意料 先生
Will you two excuse me?
两位恕我告退了?
I think perhaps this way, sir.
请这边走 先生
Yeah
对
Alfred, they need some more wine in the front room...
阿福 前面还需要些酒
and someone named Mrs. Daley needs a copy of the menu.
戴尔太太还需要一份菜单
And give Knox a grant.
对了 捐点钱给诺克
Nice talking with you, Wayne.
很高兴跟你聊 韦恩
The rich...
富人
You know why they're so odd? Because they can afford to be.
知道他们为什么怪异吗? 因为有钱经得起
Look at this mirror.
你看这面镜子
Maybe it should be Bruce Vain.
该叫布鲁斯浮华的
- Robert, what's up? - Anonymous tip.
- 罗勃 什么事? - 匿名情报
Napier's cleaning out Axis Chemicals.
纳皮尔扫荡了艾克斯厂
If we could put our hands on him, we'd have Grissom.
只要逮了他 格里森也跑不了
Why wasn't I told about this? Who's in charge?
为何没人告诉我? 谁负责的?
- Eckhardt, sir. - Oh, my God!
- 艾哈特 - 要命!
Come on, let's go.
咱们走
All right. Take a good look. This is the guy.
你看清楚了 就是他
(通缉犯: 杰克纳皮尔)
All right, get a good look.
看个清楚
Shoot to kill. You know what I mean?
格杀勿论 懂我意思吧?
All right, let's move out.
好了 出发吧
We've been ratted out here, boys.
我们被摆道了 各位
Watch it.
小心
Freeze!
不准动!
You, left. You take the right. Move it.
你 左边 你去右翼 快
What the hell's going on?
怎么回事?
What are you trying to do? Blow the collar?
你想干什么? 泄底吗?
I'm in charge here, not Carl Grissom.
这儿由我负责 不是卡尔格里森
This is Commissioner Gordon. I want him taken alive.
我是高登局长 我要抓活口
I repeat. Any man who opens fire on Jack Napier will answer to me.
重覆一次 谁开枪打伤杰克 就得对我负责
Let me down!
放我下来!
Oh, my God!
哦 天呀!
He went that way!
他在那边!
See if you can get up on the catwalk on that side.
到那边的窄道上看看
You take that side. Be careful. Be very careful.
你守那一边 务必小心 千万别大意
Jesus!
老天爷!
Let him go, or I'll do Gordon!
放了他 否则我就杀高登!
Nice outfit.
好漂亮的行头
Come on, Jack, let's go!
快呀 杰克 咱们走!
Come on! Jack!
快点! 杰克!
Eckhardt!
艾哈特!
Think about the future.
替未来想一下
God damn it, we had him.
他妈的 已经到手了
Hold it right there!
不准动!
- Who is this guy? - I don't know.
- 那小子是谁? - 不知道
Until we find out, keep a lid on it.
查明真相前 别说出去
Wait. If there's no Bat, then who dropped this guy, Napier, into the acid?
等等 如果真没蝙蝠侠 是谁把杰克丢进硫酸中?
Suicide? Wait, I want to get this on tape.
自杀呀? 等等 我要录音
Hello?
喂?
He hung up. What have you got?
他挂了 你找到了什么?
Here's the inner city, there's Axis Chemicals...
这是市内 这是艾克斯厂
and here's the sightings so far.
这是露面的地点
Maybe Batman has some kind of flight pattern or something.
蝙蝠侠可能有固定的飞行路线
That's all I can think of.
这是我的想法
This is very good. I'll tell you what...
非常好 这样好了
tonight, first I'll take you to dinner, then we'll walk the trail.
今晚先请你去吃饭 然后去散个步
No can do. I got a date. With Bruce Wayne.
不行 我和布鲁斯韦恩先约好了
Wayne! Wayne! Oh, no!
韦恩! 韦恩! 不行!
How about you?
你又能怎么样?
The guy's a stiff. He's a rich stiff, but you could do much better.
那家伙是个呆头鹅 配不上你
Thanks for being so concerned. Bye.
谢谢你的关心 再见
How's the soup?
汤还好吧?
Excuse me?
对不起?
The soup. How is it?
我说汤 怎么样?
It's great.
太好了
Could you pass the salt?
盐传过来好吗?
Sure.
好的
Thanks.
谢谢
Did you have a hard time finding the house?
我家好找吗?
- No, it was no problem. - Good.
- 很容易 没问题 - 好
Do you like eating in here?
你喜欢在这儿吃饭?
Yeah.
对
You want to know the truth, I don't think I've ever been in this room before.
老实说我以前没来过这里
Do you want to get out of here?
你想出去吗?
Yes.
对
There was young Master Bruce...
布鲁斯主人小时候
leading his gray pony with me on its back...
骑着一匹小灰马跟着我
like a sack of old potatoes, covered in mud and nursing a sprained ankle.
像一袋老土豆 全身是泥 脚踝扭伤正在治疗
That was the first and last time I gave him a riding lesson.
那是我有生第一次也是最后一次 教他骑术
I think I've embarrassed him for long enough.
那一次让他一直很尴尬
I'm off to bed.
我该去睡了
Please, leave everything. I'll tidy up in the morning.
拜托 不用动 我明早再收拾
- Good night, miss. - Good night, Alfred.
- 晚安 小姐 - 晚安 阿福
- Good night, sir. - Good night, Alfred.
- 晚安 先生 - 晚安 阿福
He's really wonderful. He loves you a lot.
他真好 他很爱你
Alfred's great. I couldn't find my socks without him.
阿福是很棒 连袜子都得靠他找
He sort of reminds me of my grandfather.
他令我想起我爷爷
Were you close to him?
你们很亲吗?
Yeah, I used to spend summers with him and my grandmother.
对 我常和他及奶奶 一起过暑假
They had a house on the lake. Nothing like this, but...
他们住在湖边 虽比不上你家 可是
it was fun.
很好玩
- That sounds nice. - Yeah.
- 不错嘛 - 对
What about your family?
你的家人呢?
Actually, Alfred is my family.
其实 只有阿福
This house and all this stuff really doesn't seem like you at all.
这里的一切似乎跟你很不衬
Some of it is very much me.
有些东西很像我
Some of it isn't.
有些不是
That dining room is definitely not you.
餐厅绝对不像
The dining room isn't.
对 没错
(手术室)
- Let's see how we did. - Yeah.
- 看看结果吧 - 好
Oh, my God!
哦 天啊!
Mirror.
镜子
Mirror!
拿镜子来!
You understand that the nerves were completely severed.
你知道神经已完全毁了
You see what I have to work with here.
你也看到我用什么工具了
There's an awful lot of stairs in this place.
这地方到处是楼梯
My feet are killing me.
两条腿快断了
Okay.
好了
I feel a little drunk. And you're not anything.
我有点醉了 你却没事
One drink and I'm flying.
再一杯下肚就要飞了
Why are you afraid of flying?
你害怕飞行不成?
That you, sugar bumps?
是你吗 小甜点?
Who the hell are you?
你是谁?
It's me.
是我
"Sugar bumps."
"小甜点"
Jack.
杰克
Thank God, you're alive! I heard you'd been...
谢天谢地 你没死! 我听说你
Fried?
烫死了?
Is that what you heard?
你是这么听说的?
You set me up over a woman.
为了一个娘们陷害我
A woman!
一个娘们!
You must be insane.
你八成是疯了
Don't bother.
免了吧
Your life won't be worth spit!
你命狗屎不值!
I've been dead once already.
我已经死了一次
It's very liberating.
感觉很自由
You should think of it as therapy.
不妨当做是一种治疗
Jack, listen.
杰克 听我说
Maybe we can cut a deal.
或许咱俩可以谈个条件
Jack?
杰克?
Jack is dead, my friend.
杰克早死了 朋友
You can call me...
叫我
Joker.
丑客
And as you can see...
你也看得出来
I'm a lot happier.
我比过去更快乐了
What a day.
光荣的日子
Gotham City.
哥谭市呀
It always brings a smile to my face.
我一见你就笑
"Winged freak...
"飞行怪胎
"terrorizes..."
"人心惶惶"
Wait till they get a load of me.
还没见识过老子呢
I've got an idea. How about lunch at my place?
我有个妙计 到我家吃午饭?
I'll show you some photos.
给你看些照片
Sure. Okay.
好呀 好
Wait a minute. No, I can't. I can't make it.
等一下 我不能去 我抽不出空
Okay, we'll do it later in the day.
好吧 晚点再去
Hold on a second.
不行
I can't make it then, either. I've got a very important meeting today.
晚点也不成 今天有个重要的会议
What's wrong?
怎么了?
Nothing's wrong.
没什么
Really. I've just got to go out of town on business for a few days.
真的 我只想离开几天
- Okay, we'll do it when you get back. - All right.
- 好吧 等你回来再说 - 好的
I got to go. I'm late.
我该走了 不早了
Bye.
再见
Jesus.
老天
Alfred.
阿福
- It's nice to see you again, ma'am. - Nice to see you, too.
- 真高兴又见到你 小姐 - 彼此
I'll talk to you guys when you get back.
等你们回来再说罗
Back, Miss Vale? We're going to be here for quite a while.
回来? 可能要好一阵哟
Well, bye.
好吧 再见
Honey...
甜心
you'll never believe what happened to me today.
你绝不相信我今天的遭遇
So, gentlemen, that's how it is. Until Grissom resurfaces...
各位 情况就是如此 在格里森露面之前
I'm the acting president.
我是代理董事长
And I say, starting with this anniversary festival...
我决定在周年纪念日
we run this city into the ground.
攻击哥谭市
Why don't we hear this from Grissom?
为什么不等格里森决定?
Yeah.
对
And what's with that stupid grin?
他奸笑个什么劲?
Life's been good to me.
上帝对我很眷顾
What if we say "no"?
如果我们拒绝呢?
Well, Tony...
东尼呀
nobody wants a war.
没人喜欢战争
If we can't do business, we'll just shake hands and that'll be it.
生意不成仁义在 我们握手言和
Yeah?
是吗?
Yeah
没错
I got a live one here.
还有电呢
There'll be a hot time in the old town tonight
本镇今晚有的瞧罗
Antoine got a little hot under the collar.
东尼一定火冒三丈罗
You're crazy.
你疯了
Haven't you ever heard of the healing power of laughter?
你可曾听过一笑治百病 这句话?
- Now get out of here! - You heard him. Let's go! Move it!
- 给我滚! - 你们都听到了 走! 快走!
You think it over.
你们想清楚
Let's go, come on. Get out of here.
快走 快 滚出去
Move it!
快走!
Bob
巴勃
I want you to go down to the Globe, follow that reporter Knox.
你去镜报跟踪诺克
Take your camera.
带着照相机去
See what he knows about this Batman.
看他对蝙蝠侠知道多少
And, Bob...
还有巴勃
remember, you...
切记 你
are my number one guy.
你是我的左右手
Yes, sir.
是的
Your pals...
我的朋友
they're not bad people.
都不算坏人
Maybe we...
我们不妨
ought to give them a couple of days to think it over.
给他们几天时间考虑一下
No?
不行?
Grease them now?
现在就杀他们?
Okay.
好吧
You are a vicious bastard, Rotelli.
你是个大奸包 洛泰里
I'm glad you're dead.
你死了活该
I'm glad he's dead.
I need that.
我正需要
I'm losing confidence in you. I thought we were a team.
我快对你失去信心了 我以为咱们是一伙的
This wouldn't be a personal issue for you, would it?
是你的私人问题吧?
I just want you to do your job.
我只要你尽到责任
I am doing my job.
我是在尽责任
Me, too. I'm protecting my partner.
我也是 我在保护伙伴
There's nothing in these files. No photos, no histories, no nothing. Who is this guy?
档案中查不出任何照片或资料 他是什么人?
Who cares?
管他的?
Forget about Bruce Wayne. I'm on to Batman.
别管布鲁斯韦恩了 我要采访蝙蝠侠
They should be out here any second.
他们马上就要出发
I can't wait to hear the explanation for this one.
我等着听他们如何解释
Here he comes, man.
他来了 老兄
What is this affidavit you filed?
你公证什么文件?
Grissom gave you all his businesses?
格里森把所有事业都交给你了?
Mr. Grissom asked me, as a personal favor...
格里森先生以私情委托我
to take over the operation of his businesses until he returns.
接管他的事业 直到他回来为止
That's a pretty big favor. You two must have been very close.
这倒是个大人情 你俩关系八成不错
Very close.
很不错
Did you do a little time together as children?
小时候一起吃过牢饭?
Our accountants are looking into it. We assure you, the affidavit is legitimate.
我方的会计会查阅的 委任书是合法的
I smell fresh ink, guys. You can prove all this?
我闻到墨水味 你能证明吗?
What am I asking? Of course you can.
我胡扯些什么? 他当然能了
We have witnesses. Grissom's signature is perfectly legitimate.
我们有证人 格里森的签名完全合法
It is legitimate.
是合法的
I saw it. I was there.
我看见了 我在场
I saw it all.
全部看见了
He reached up with his dead hand...
他伸出死手
and signed it in his own blood.
用鲜血签的
And he did it...with this pen.
他用这支笔写的
Hello, Vinnie. It's your uncle Bingo.
哈罗 文尼 我是你宾果叔叔呀
Time to pay the check.
该还债了
The pen...
笔
is truly mightier than the sword.
的确比剑有力
Get down!
趴下!
Doesn't this gang war dampen the city's plans for the 200th anniversary festival?
帮派火拼会影响周年纪念活动吗?
The festival opens. The police are gonna stop these gangsters.
活动照常举行 警方会阻止那些歹徒
Mr. Dent, what do you think about the theory...
丹特先生 你对蝙蝠侠是黑社会组织
that the mysterious Batman is a mob enforcer killing these men?
的说法有何意见?
I don't have any comment.
恕不奉告
Batman.
蝙蝠侠
Can somebody tell me what kind of a world we live in...
人穿蝙蝠装
where a man dressed up as a bat...
这成了什么世界呀
gets all of my press?
抢尽我的风头?
This town needs an enema!
本市需要通个便!
Alfred.
阿福
May I have a glass of water?
给我杯水好吗?
I'm relieved that you're home, sir.
你回来令我很安慰
Miss Vale telephoned. She was rather concerned.
瓦尔小姐来电话 她很关心呢
I feel that there's a certain weight that lifts when she is here.
她来过之后 好像安心多了
Alfred...
阿福
why don't you marry her?
你干脆娶她算了?
That's not exactly what I had in mind, sir.
我没有这个打算
No.
不要
I can't go on with that right now.
我此刻无法思考这件事
If not now...
现在不想
when?
几时?
I don't know.
不知道
I just found out Jack Napier's still alive.
我听说杰克纳皮尔还活着
He's running Grissom's men. I need all the information the police have on him.
接管了格里森的事业 我需要一切警方的资料
- Yes, sir. - Thank you.
- 是的 - 谢谢你
Alfred.
阿福
She is great, isn't she?
她很棒 对吧?
Yes, sir.
对
- City room, Knox. - Hi.
- 市政府 诺克 - 嗨
- I want you to check something out for me. - Sure.
- 帮我查点资料好吗? - 说吧
Find out what's so special about the alley at Pearl and Phillips Streets.
查一下珍珠和菲力浦街 有什么不寻常的
- Pearl and Phillips? - Yeah.
- 珍珠和菲力浦? - 对
You got it.
没问题
Okay.
好
Okay, bye.
再见了
Mr. Wayne.
韦恩先生
So much to do and so little time.
事情这么多 时间不够用的
The photos.
照片
Who's that loss?
那个废物是谁?
It's Knox.
诺克
Bad tie. No style.
丑领带 没格调
Stop the press!
一切暂停!
- Who is that? - That's Vicki Vale.
- 她是什么人? - 维琪瓦尔
She's the photographer who's working with Knox.
和诺克一起的摄影师
That girl has style.
这姑娘有味道
Jesus marimba!
乖乖隆地咚!
A lovely beast like that running around...
这么迷人的娘们
could put steam in a man's strides.
哪个男人见了不来劲的
She's dating some guy named Wayne.
她和一个叫韦恩的人一起
She's about to trade up.
她快要升级了
It's hard to stay inside the lines.
很难剪得齐
I'm about...
我就要有
to get a new girl, Bobby.
新女人了 巴勃
I'm of a mind to make some mooky.
我此时哈的要死
- Phone book. - Yes, sir.
- 电话簿 - 遵命
So much to do...
事情这么多
and so little time.
时间总觉不够
(艾克斯化学公司)
Have you shipped a million of those things?
你运出一百万桶了吗?
Yes, sir.
是的
Ship them all! We're going to take them out a whole new door!
全运出去 咱们要改变整个规模!
Ten seconds to transmission.
再十秒钟
Five, four...
五 四
three, two, one.
三 二 一
Cue music.
音乐
Cue Becky.
贝琪
Good evening. The fashion world was stunned today...
晚上好 当今的流行界
by the sudden deaths of models Candy Walker and Amanda Keeler.
因模特儿甘蒂华克 和艾曼达吉勒之死而震惊
Cause of death has been attributed to a violent allergic reaction...
据说死因是强烈的过敏反应
although authorities have not ruled out the possibility of drug use.
当局也不排除药物致死的可能性
Peter.
彼得
And plans continue for the city's 200th birthday...
市长今天在揭幕式中宣布
as Mayor Borg announced today at the unveiling...
周年活动按计划举行
This just in.
这是刚送来的
Three mysterious deaths at a beauty parlor...
哥谭市一家美容院 今天发现一连发生
At a beauty parlor in Gotham were discovered today.
三起神秘死亡事件
What the hell's going on?
到底是怎么搞的?
Becky, this is hardly the...
贝琪 这种行为太
Becky.
贝琪
Kill the camera.
摄影机关掉
This is Rene on the news floor.
我是蕾妮 在新闻摄影棚
I need some paramedics up here now.
我需要一些镇静剂
New and improved Joker products!
新上市丑客产品!
With a new secret ingredient.
内含秘密成份
Smylex!
含笑素!
What is this?
怎么回事?
Now, let's go over...
我们再继续
to our blind taste test.
无偏见的口味
Love that Joker.
我爱那个丑客
- Where's it coming from? - I don't know.
- 从哪来的? - 不知道
He don't look happy. He's been using brand X.
他不太快乐 他使用的是X牌的
But with new and improved Joker brand...
有了新的丑客牌之后
I get a grin again...
我脸上再度展露笑容
and again.
永不消失
That luscious tan...
还有美丽的古铜色
those ruby lips...
宝红双唇
and hair color so natural, only your undertaker knows for sure.
还有自然的发色 只有殡仪馆的人才知道
I know what you're saying:
我懂你说些什么:
"Where can I get these fine, new items? "
"我到哪去买这么好的货品? "
That's the gag. Chances are, you bought them already!
妙处就在这 其实你已经买过了!
Love that Joker.
我爱丑客
So, remember...
别忘了
put on a happy face.
随时保持笑容
- The information you requested. - Thank you.
- 你要的资料 先生 - 谢谢你
"Jack Napier, assault with a deadly weapon, age 15.
杰克纳皮尔 15岁 以致命武器攻击
"Results of psychological profile...
"心理测试结果
"violent mood swings, highly intelligent, emotionally unstable.
"心智失常 智慧极高 情绪极度不稳
"Aptitudes include science, chemistry, and art."
"性格取向包括科学 化学 和艺术"
Chemistry.
化学
- Alfred, let's go shopping. - Yes, sir.
- 阿福 我们去购物 - 好的
(化妆品带来恐慌)
Six new deaths, with no clues as to the Joker's deadly weapon.
又有六人死亡 然而丑客的致命武器 仍无线索
And what is the pattern?
下毒的货品有哪些?
Foods, alcohol, or beauty and hygiene products?
食物 酒精 美容及卫生产品?
Cologne, mouthwash, underarm deodorant?
古龙水 漱口水 腋下除臭剂?
Or worse yet, there may be no pattern.
最糟的是 找不出固定的模式来
The search goes on through Gotham's shopping nightmare.
警方继续搜索哥谭市各个购物中心
We are going to have a festival if I have to get a shotgun to get people there myself.
活动照计划举行 即使要我用猎枪 也在所不惜
Do you hear the words coming out of my mouth? The festival is on!
你听清楚了吗? 活动照常举行!
And you find out what this madman is poisoning us with.
你马上去查出那个疯子 用的是什么毒药
And fast. Do you read me?
快去 懂了吗?
We're working on it. I need all the help I can get.
我们正在研究 我需要各方面的支援
Bruce, hi. It's Vicki.
布鲁斯 嗨 我是维琪
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna be 10 minutes late to the museum.
抱歉 我可能晚十分钟才能到博物馆
I'll see you when I get there. Bye.
见面再谈 再见
Sir, a message from Miss Vale.
先生 是瓦尔小姐的口信
She'll be 10 minutes late in meeting you at the museum.
她会迟到十分钟
Okay, fine, thank you. Wait a minute, Alfred.
好的 谢谢你 等一下 阿福
I'm not meeting her today.
我今天没有约她
Jack, where are you going?
杰克 你去哪呀?
Daddy's going to make some art, darling.
我要去创作艺术 亲爱的
Excuse me. Mr. Wayne's table?
对不起 韦恩先生的桌位?
Yes. He hasn't arrived yet.
他还没到
We have a table waiting.
桌子已摆好了
All right.
好的
Miss Vale, this just arrived for you.
瓦尔小姐 这是刚送到的
(马上戴上去)
Gentlemen!
各位!
Let's broaden our minds. Lawrence.
我们来扩展一下见识 劳伦斯
Give him a shave.
刮个胡子
Terence, brush.
泰伦斯 画笔
(丑客在此)
The one-dollar bill.
一元钞票
Hold it!
等一下!
I kind of like this one, Bob. Leave it.
我蛮喜欢这一幅的 巴勃 别戳破
You can take that off now, I think.
可以摘下来了
You're beautiful in an old-fashioned kind of way.
你很漂亮 很有古典美
But I'm sure we can make you more today.
我有办法让你更现代化
Is that your portfolio?
是你的手提箱吗?
I'm meeting someone who wants to see my work.
我约了人来看我作品的
Crap.
废物
Crap...
废物废物
Now that's good work.
这是好作品
The skulls, the bodies.
骷髅 尸体
You give it such a glow. I don't know if it's art, but I like it.
被你一拍就很惹眼 艺术我虽不懂 我很喜欢
Let me tell you what I'm thinking about, sweetie.
让我告诉你 我的想法吧 美人
I was in the bath one day...
我有一天正在洗澡
when I realized why I was destined for greatness.
突然发觉 自己天生就是个伟人
You know how concerned people are about appearances.
你知道一般人多注重外表
This is attractive, that is not.
这个人迷人 这个人很丑
That is all behind me. I now do what other people only dream.
那一切都过去了 我现在的一切是别人梦想不到的
I make art. Until someone dies.
我创作艺术 直到有人死为止
See?
懂吧?
I am the world's first fully-functioning homicidal artist.
我是世界第一个全自动化杀人艺术家
What do you want?
你想干什么?
My face on the one-dollar bill.
我的照片印在一元钞票上
You must be joking.
笑话
Do I look like I'm joking?
我的表情像吗?
Well...
不像
Listen.
听我说
We mustn't compare ourselves to regular people. We're artists.
我们不能和平凡人去比 我们是艺术家
For instance, let me challenge you with a little piece I did.
比方说 我拿一幅作品跟你挑战
Bob. Alicia.
巴勃 爱莉雪
You will take pictures and record my work.
你用照片纪录我的作品
You will join me in the avant-garde of the new aesthetic.
跟我加入前卫艺术之列
Jack, you said I could watch you improve the paintings.
杰克 你说我可以看你修改画的
I'm in trouble now.
出了点问题
Why is she wearing a mask?
她干嘛戴面具?
She's just a sketch, really.
其实只是张草图
Alicia, sit down. Show the lady why you wear the mask.
爱莉雪 坐下 告诉她你为何戴面具
You see, Miss Vale, Alicia's been made over in line with my new philosophy.
你知道 瓦尔小姐 她和我有共同的人生哲学
So now, like me...
所以她和我一样
she is a living work of art.
是幅活动艺术品
I'm no Picasso, but do you like it?
我不是毕卡索 不过你会喜欢吗?
It's great.
太棒了
So, what can I do for you?
要我帮什么忙?
A little song, a little dance.
唱首歌 跳支舞
Batman's head on a lance.
蝙蝠侠的头吊在绳子上
Tell me, what do you know about...
告诉我 你知道多少
I don't know anything about Batman.
我对他一无所知
Really?
真的吗?
Well, how about a little "you and me"?
咱俩热呼一下如何?
You're insane.
你疯了
I thought I was a Pisces. Come on.
我以为我是双鱼宫的 来吧
Let's make up. Have a little...
咱们交合一下
whiff of my posy.
闻闻我的小牡丹
Help me!
救命呀!
I'm melting!
我快要溶化了!
I'm melting! Help me! I'm melting!
我快要溶化了! 救命呀! 我快要溶化了!
Boo.
嘣
Hold on.
抱紧
Where does he get those wonderful toys?
他哪来的好玩意?
- Get in the car. - Which one?
- 上车 - 哪一辆?
Let's go.
快走
Shields.
盾甲
How much do you weigh?
你多重?
About 108, I think.
108磅吧
Hold on.
抓稳
See that thing on my belt? Grab it.
看见我腰带上的东西吗? 抓住
Whatever you do, don't let go.
无论如何 别放手
No blood.
没有血
Who is this guy?
那家伙是谁?
Check his wallet.
查一下皮夹
- Wait a minute. - What is that?
- 等等 - 那是什么?
Some kind of body armor. He's human after all.
是胄甲 他终究还是个人
Take off the mask.
面具脱掉
Shoot her!
开枪!
Shields open.
盾甲开
You weigh a little more than 108.
你不只108磅
- Really? - Let's go.
- 真的? - 快走
Stop.
停
Where are we going?
我们去哪?
Be careful.
小心点
Bats.
蝙蝠
They're great survivors.
生存能力很强
- What is all this? - The police have got it wrong.
- 这是什么玩意? - 警方搞错了
They're looking for one product.
他们以为只有一种产品
The Joker's tainted hundreds of chemicals at the source.
丑客在上百种货品中下毒
Then whole shipments of products would be poisoned.
整批货都会有毒
And we'd all be dead.
我们都会死
No.
不会
The poison only works when components are mixed. Hairspray won't do it alone.
成份混合后毒药才会生效 喷发水单独不起作用
But hairspray mixed with lipstick and perfume will be toxic, and untraceable.
但若和香水 唇膏混合 就会有毒了
How did you figure this out?
你怎么知道的?
Take that to the press.
这个拿去报社
I might have some trouble with that.
这么做有点困难
A lot of people think you're as dangerous as the Joker.
很多人认为 你和丑客一样危险
He's psychotic.
他是丧心病狂
Some people say the same thing about you.
也有人这么说你
What people?
什么人?
Well, I mean, let's face it.
面对现实吧
You're not exactly normal. Are you?
你并非正常人 对吧?
It's not exactly a normal world, is it?
这也不算个正常世界
Why did you bring me here?
为何带我来此?
You could have sent that stuff to the press yourself.
你大可自己送去报社的
You're right.
说的对
There is something else you have that I want.
你拥有我想要的东西
What?
什么?
He took the film.
他把底片拿走了
Yeah.
是啊
Where have you been? Are you all right? Do you want me to come on over?
你去哪了? 还好吧? 要我过去吗?
No, Allie.
不要了 亚历山大
If I bring something to you, can we make the evening edition?
如果我现在送新闻来 赶得上晚间版吗?
Just barely. Is it hot?
还来得及 好爆吗?
Yeah, it's real hot.
对 保证大爆
Yeah, bye.
好的 再见
- Copy! - Yes, sir?
- 校对! - 是的?
Avoid the following combinations:
避免下列的合用情形:
Deodorants with baby powder, hairspray, and lipstick.
除臭剂不能与婴儿粉 喷发水和唇膏并用
Safe products are flying in as Gotham City goes on a forced fast.
安全产品在哥谭市上空 大量空投
And all of Gotham is wondering what to make of Batman.
市民对这位蝙蝠侠 不知如何看待
Friend or foe?
是友还是敌?
I have given a name to my pain...
我眼中长出一根刺
and it is Batman.
蝙蝠侠
You must possess strength to inflict pain, Bob.
要对抗痛苦首需力量 巴勃
We've got a flying mouse to kill...
有只飞鼠待宰
and I want to clean my claws.
我要磨爪以待
Sir, Miss Vale called again.
瓦尔小姐又来电了
Dare I suggest that your present course of action...
你目前的行为
might simply strengthen her resolve?
只会强化她的决心?
She is quite tenacious.
她很机巧
You're right about that.
说的对
And if I may say so, quite special. Perhaps you could try telling her the truth.
恕我直言 也很特别 不妨考虑对她说实话
Coming.
来了
Hi.
嗨
May I come in?
可以进去吗?
This is a nice apartment.
好漂亮的房子
Lots of space.
空间也好大
Listen, I came over to...
我是来
- clear a few things... - I don't know who you think you are!
- 澄清几件事的 - 你自以为是什么!
- You hurt me. - I know.
- 你伤了我 - 我知道
I called you and I called you. And you lied! You lied about leaving town.
我不断打电话给你 你却一直骗我! 骗我说要出城
- Let me tell you why. - Let me tell you!
- 我告诉你原因吧 - 我告诉你好了!
You invited me out, we went to dinner.
你邀我吃饭
I thought we felt something. And I trusted you.
我以为彼此很投缘 我相信你
I even slept with you. I can't believe I did that.
跟你睡觉 我不信自己这么做
Then you wouldn't return my calls. You must be some kind of jerk.
你却连个电话也不回 你八成是个变态
You're a real nice girl and I like you a lot, but right now, shut up.
你是个好女孩 我好喜欢你 不过你先闭嘴
I have something I have to tell you.
我有话要说
You know how people have different sides to their personality?
你知道人的性格是多变的?
Sometimes...
有时候
a person will have to actually lead a different life.
不得不过另一种生活
Oh, my God, you're married.
我的天 你结婚了
No, I'm not married.
我没结婚
You see...
其实
my life is really...
我的生活很
complex.
复杂
All right, listen. You know how a normal person gets up and...
好 你听着 你知道正常人一起床
goes downstairs...
就下楼
and eats breakfast...
吃早饭
and kisses somebody good-bye, and goes to...
跟家人吻别
a job and, you know.
去上班 你懂
No.
不懂
No?
不懂?
All right, look.
好吧 听着
Vicki, what I'm trying to tell you is...
维琪 我要说的是
Hey, it's okay.
嘿 没关系
- You can tell me. - Okay.
- 告诉我无妨 - 好的
What I'm trying to tell you is...
我要说的是
is a ...
其实
- I'll be right back. - All right.
- 我马上回来 - 好的
Miss me?
想我吗?
Nice place you got here. Lots of space.
你家真美 空间好大
Vicki, we really should have a talk.
维琪 咱们得谈谈
I'm very upset.
真气人
We were having dinner.
我们吃过饭
I was a man doing well with a beautiful woman.
我一向在美女面前一把罩
And without so much as an apology...
你却一个抱歉也不说
you ran off with that sideshow phony.
就跟那个小瘪三走了
You know, Vic...
你知道
I've recently had a tragedy in my life.
我最近发生了悲剧
Alicia...
爱莉雪
threw herself out of the window.
跳窗自杀了
Oh, my God.
天呀
But...
可是
you can't make an omelet without breaking some eggs.
塞翁失马焉知非福
Well, Ms. Vale...
瓦尔小姐呀
another rooster in the hen-house?
窝里还有只公鸡呀?
Take thy beak from out my heart.
简直令我伤心欲绝
Bruce?
布鲁斯?
Bruce Wayne, n'est-ce pas?
布鲁斯韦恩 对吗? ?
Most of the time.
大部份时候是
I know who you are.
我知道你是谁
Let me tell you about this guy I know, Jack.
我说给你听吧 杰克
Mean kid. Bad seed. Hurt people.
下流 龌龊 专门害人
I like him already.
我已经喜欢上他了
You know what the problem was?
知道问题在那吗?
He got sloppy. You know, crazy.
他短路 疯狂
He started to lose it. He had a head full of bad wiring, I guess.
他已经成不了气候了 满肚子烂肠烂肉
Couldn't keep it straight up here.
脑袋已经报销了
He was the kind of guy who...
他是个
couldn't hear the train until it was 2 feet from him.
不见棺材不流泪的人
You know what happened to this guy, Jack?
知道他的下场吗?
Listen.
听着
He made mistakes.
他犯了错
Then he ended up with his lights out! Now you want to get nuts?
后来就发了疯! 你也想发疯吗?
Come on! Let's get nuts!
来吧! 大伙一起疯!
Tell me something, my friend.
告诉我件事
You ever dance with the devil in the pale moonlight?
可曾在月光下和魔鬼共舞过?
What?
什么?
I always ask that of all my prey.
我经常这样问每一个枪下鬼
I just like the sound of it.
我只是喜欢听那种声音
Never rub another man's rhubarb.
不要随便挑人的针眼
Why is it every time we got company...
为什么每次找你
somebody always gets in the way?
总是杀出程咬金来?
I'll need a moment alone, boys.
我需要独处一下
I'm only laughing on the outside.
我只是笑在脸上
My smile is just skin-deep.
内心痛苦无比
If you could see inside...
但愿你看得透我
I'm really crying.
心在哭泣
You might join me for a weep.
你会陪我痛哭一场的
You wouldn't believe it. You really wouldn't.
说了你也不信
While you were out entertaining, I've been here finding out about your street corner.
你乐得去享受 我却到处找你
Vale
瓦尔
I think your friend Wayne is really screwed up.
你朋友完蛋了
More good news.
还有更精彩的
Here.
你瞧
(汤玛斯韦恩被害 儿子幸免)
Oh, my God!
我的天!
His parents were murdered in that alley.
他父母在那被谋害
That's why he went there.
所以他才会去那
Poor kid watched the whole thing happen in front of him.
他当场目睹一切
Look at the look on the face.
瞧他脸上的表情
It was the same in front of City Hall.
和在市政府时一样
What do you suppose something like this does to a kid?
这种事对孩子的影响会有多大?
Vale
瓦尔
Don't get personal!
别太感性了!
Alfred
阿福
Did you get the file on my parents?
我父母的档案弄到了吗?
It's on your table, sir.
全在你桌上
Thank you.
谢谢你
What's on your mind, Alfred?
你想些什么 阿福?
I have no wish to fill my few remaining years...
我不想在余年
grieving for the loss of old friends...
再为朋友的死伤神
or their sons.
或者朋友的儿子
The 200th anniversary birthday gala has been indefinitely postponed.
两百周年纪念活动 无限延期
We simply cannot guarantee public safety...
我们无力保证大众的安全
Joker here.
我是丑客
We got interference. Call the OB unit.
有干扰 通知人去修
Now you fellows have said some pretty mean things...
你们说了些丑话
some of which were true...
有些是真的
under that fiend, Boss Grissom.
由那个魔头 格里森口中说出
He was a thief and a terrorist.
他是个贼 也是恐怖份子
On the other hand, he had a tremendous singing voice.
不过嘛 他的歌声很美
He's dead now, and he's left me in charge.
他已经作古了 并交我接管
Now, I can be theatrical...
我可能有点戏剧化
and maybe even a little rough.
也或许凶了点
But one thing I am not...
不过我绝不是个
is a killer!
杀人凶手!
I'm an artist.
我是个艺术家
I love a good party.
我喜欢派对
So, truce.
和谈
Commence au festival!
周年庆照常举行!
And I've got a surprise for Gotham City.
我有个惊喜送哥谭市民
At midnight, I will dump $20 million in cash...
今天午夜我要当众洒下
on the crowd.
两千万美元
Don't worry about me. I've got enough.
不用担心 我多的是钱
We are not prepared to discuss any deals.
我们绝不谈条件
You heard it, folks, $20 million.
各位听到了 两千万哪
And there will be entertainment.
还有余兴节目
The big dukeroo. With me in one corner, and in the other corner...
生死决战 一边是我 另一边是
the man who has brought real terror to Gotham City...
给哥谭市制造恐怖的人
Batman.
蝙蝠侠
Can you hear me?
你听到了吧?
Just the two of us.
你我俩决战
Mano y mano.
空手单挑
I have taken off my make-up.
我以真面目相见
Let's see...
看你
if you can take off yours.
有没有种
Tell me, kid.
告诉我 小鬼
You ever dance with the devil by the pale moonlight?
你曾在月光下和魔鬼共舞过吗?
Let's go!
快走!
Let's go, Jack!
快走 杰克!
See you around, kid.
后会有期
Thanks.
谢谢
Hi.
嗨
Tell me if I'm crazy.
我疯了吗
But that wasn't just another night for either of us, was it?
今晚与过去不一样吧?
I mean, we both got to each other, didn't we?
我是说 我们拥有对方是吗?
Why won't you let me in?
为何不接受我?
Why?
为什么?
You got in.
我接受了
I've loved you since I met you.
第一次见面我就爱上了你
But I don't know what to think of all this. I really don't.
但我想不透这一切 真的不懂
Sometimes I don't know what to think about this.
有时候连我也一样
It's just something I have to do.
我势必要做的事
Why?
为什么?
Because nobody else can.
因为没有别人能
I tried to avoid all this, but I can't.
我企图逃避这一切 但我没办法
This is how it is.
事情就是如此
It's not a perfect world.
世界并不完美
It doesn't have to be a perfect world.
世界不必非完美不可
I just gotta know, are we going to try to love each other?
我只想知道 我们是否要彼此相爱?
I'd like to.
我愿意一试
But he's out there right now.
他还在外面猖狂
And I've got to go to work.
我得做事了
Into the air, Junior Birdman!
上天吧 小飞人!
Missed me!
失手了!
Yeah! Watch me!
瞧我的!
Get them. Take the pictures.
快点拍
Gotham's greed.
哥谭市民贪婪图
And now, folks...
各位乡亲父老
it's time for, "Who Do You Trust?"
该选最信任的人的时候了?
Money, money! Who do you trust?
钱钱钱呀! 你们信任谁?
Me? I'm giving away free money.
我吗? 我无条件洒钞票呀
And where is the Batman?
而蝙蝠侠呢?
He's at home, washing his tights.
他却在家里 洗丝袜
Winged battle flies through the night and finds me ready.
大苍蝇夜空翱翔 却发现我早胸有成竹
Bob. Mask.
巴勃 面罩
Masks! Put them on now!
面罩! 戴面罩!
And now...
现在
comes the part...
是我要
where I relieve you, the little people...
拯救你们
of the burden of your failed...
于无意义生活
and useless lives.
的时候了
But, as my plastic surgeon always said, "If you got to go...
正如我的美容师说的 "既然非死不可
"go with a smile."
"就带着笑走"
Oh, my God!
我的天!
Smylex gas.
是毒气
He's going to kill everybody!
他要毒死大家!
Get in the car. Get in the car!
上车! 上车!
Hurry!
快呀!
My balloons!
我的汽球!
Those are my balloons!
是我的汽球!
He stole my balloons!
他偷我的汽球!
Why didn't somebody tell me he had one of those things?
为什么没人告诉我 他有那玩意?
Bob. Gun.
巴勃 枪
I'm going to need a minute or two alone, boys.
给我一两分钟时间
Come on, get out of here!
快滚开!
Come on, you gruesome son of a bitch. Come to me.
来呀 你这畜牲 过来呀
Darling.
亲爱的
I've got to get you to the church on time.
我得准时送你去教堂
Yes, sir?
什么事?
Gotham City Cathedral. Transportation for two.
哥谭市大教堂 两人份交通工具
- Right away, sir? - Five minutes.
- 马上来? - 5分钟
- Better make it 10. - Okay, 10 minutes.
- 还是10分钟吧 - 好的 就10分钟
All right, let's go, men, let's go.
到了 我们走 老兄 我们走
You men go that way. Rest of you, follow me.
你们去那边 剩下的 跟我走
Let's go.
走吧
Point those searchlights up at the tower, right now! Move!
探照灯对着塔台 马上! 快!
It can be truly said that I have a bat in my belfry.
说我有点阿达的确不假
Shall we dance?
跳支舞吧?
You know, without you...
没有你
I just wouldn't want to go on.
我的日子怎么过
It's as though we were made for each other.
我俩是天作之合
Beauty and the Beast.
美女与野兽
Of course, if anyone else calls you "beast"...
如果有人当你是野兽的话
I'll rip their lungs out.
老子就挖出他的内脏
Mr. Joker?
丑客先生?
You say such beautiful things.
你说话真动听
And you're so powerful. And purple!
而你又如此强壮有力 一身大紫!
I love purple!
我喜欢紫色!
Excuse me.
对不起
Have you ever danced with the devil in the pale moonlight?
可曾在月光下和魔鬼共舞?
I'm going to kill you.
我要你的命
You idiot!
白痴!
You made me, remember?
是你害的 记得吧?
You dropped me into that vat of chemicals!
你把我丢进硫酸中的!
That wasn't easy to get over! And don't think that I didn't try.
我再努力也无法忘怀这一切!
I know you did.
是你做的
You killed my parents.
你杀了我父母
What?
什么?
What are you talking about?
你说什么?
I made you, you made me first.
我害了你 不过最初是你害我的
Hey, bat-brain, I was a kid when I killed your parents.
我当初只是个小孩
When I say I made you, you gotta say you made me.
我说你害我 你说我害你
How childish can you get?
我俩真幼稚?
You wouldn't hit a guy with glasses on, would you?
你不会打戴眼镜人吧?
What are you laughing at?
你笑什么?
Here, let me lend you a hand.
我帮忙你
Lend you a hand.
伸出援手
They don't make them like they used to!
现在人最会偷工减料了!
Hey, Batsy!
蝙仔!
There he is! Down there! Go down!
他在那! 在下面! 降低!
It's time to retire.
我该下台了
Feel free to drop in.
有空随时来玩
Sometimes I just kill myself!
有时真会笑死我!
Come on.
快点
Hold on!
抓稳!
Our police have rounded up all the Joker's men.
警方已将丑客的人 一网打尽
The reign of crime is over.
犯罪组织已消灭了
Public safety in Gotham City is no longer a laughing matter.
哥谭市的治安 已不再是笑柄了
Aren't you covering this press conference?
你不要采访记者招待会吗?
No.
不要
What about our Pulitzer Prize?
我们的普立兹奖呢?
What about us?
我们的事呢?
What about your picture of Batman?
你说的蝙蝠侠照片呢?
Take care, Allie.
保重罗
We've received a letter from Batman this morning.
我们收到蝙蝠侠的信了
"Please inform the citizens of Gotham...
"请转告哥谭市民
"that Gotham City's earned a rest from crime.
"哥谭市已无犯罪事件
"But if the forces of evil should rise again...
"万一歹徒敢再蠢动的话
"to cast a shadow on the heart of the city...
"为害哥谭市
"call me. "
"请通知我"
Question. How do we call him?
请问 如何通知他?
He gave us a signal.
他要我们放出讯号
I thought champagne would be in order, ma'am.
还是喝香槟比较适合
Hi, Alfred.
嗨 阿福
Mr. Wayne told me to tell you...
韦恩先生要我转告你
that he might be a little late.
他可能稍晚一点
I'm not a bit surprised.
我一点也不觉意外